# Michael Niemeyer

E5 / 56 Bay Street, 2007 Ultimo, Sydney

■ micniemeyer1@gmail.com
 ■ michael-niemeyer

I am a determined, focused, and very broadly interested person with learning being my deepest motivation. I am enthusiastic about mathematics, computer science, and their combination. My main research interests are computer vision and machine learning.

**Education** 

#### **University of St Andrews**

St Andrews, United Kingdom

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN ADVANCED COMPUTER SCIENCE (WITH DISTINCTION)

Sep 2016 - Sep 2017

• St Andrews GPA: 18.8 / 20

**University of Barcelona** 

Barcelona, Spain

Erasmus Exchange Year Sep 2013 - Jun 2014

• Chosen modules: English Language 1 & 2, Textual Production, Human Geography 1 & 2, Physical Geography, Climatology

University of Cologne Cologne, Germany

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN MATHEMATICS WITH MINOR GEOGRAPHY (1.8)

Sep 2012 - Dec 2015

- Bachelor's thesis title: 'Local characterisation of polyhedral spaces' (1.0)
- Supervisor: Alexander Lytchak

#### Friherr-vom-Stein-Gymnasium Kleve

Kleve, Germany Jun 2001 - Jun 2011

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA
Specialised courses: Mathematics (15/15), Physics (15/15), English (13/15), Philosophy (15/15)

• Final grade: 1.1

#### Master's Thesis

# Semantic Labelling of Images by Their Content using Non-Parametric Bayesian Machine Learning and Image Search using Synthetically Generated Images

St Andrews, United Kingdom

SUPERVISOR: DR. OGNJEN ARANDJELOVIĆ

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

- We developed an algorithm that discovers meaningful object categories and provides semantic labels for unseen images in a fully unsupervised manner
- This is realised by employing a probabilistic model from the Bayesian nonparametric framework (HDP-LDA) which detects shared clusters of quantised superpixels across the image collection
- We developed two novel approaches to provide labels for discovered object classes
- The developed algorithm can be used without any kind of tuning (e.g. choosing the number of object categories) and on any kind of image data set (from no attached information at all, to weakly-associated labels, to fully annotated) while performing on par with state-of-the-art similar applications

### **Experience**

#### Sentia Australia Pty Ltd

Sydney, Australia

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER (FULL-TIME)

Sep 2017 - Present

- · I develop front end web products in accordance to newest web development and accessibility standards (W3C)
- · Most projects follow the Ruby on Rails framework with Slim as the template language
- The clients vary from medical institutions, to established private equity firms, to newly founded start-ups, etc.

#### ecoprog GmbH

Cologne, Germany

STUDENT ASSISTANT (40 HOURS PER MONTH)

Mar 2015 - Aug 2016

1

- My usual tasks consisted of composing short technical articles for the company's newsletter, managing the database as well as developing GIS maps
- · I also completed research and other assignments for relevant projects and studies in the field of energy technology consulting

Kleve, Germany

Three-month intern

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015

• I was introduced to the local and wider computer network structures of the hospital together with other medical institutions, the setup procedure of new personal computers as well as everyday tasks of the IT department

## Extracurricular Activity \_\_\_\_\_

#### **HelpX-based Voluntary Work**

Andalucia, Spain

Jun 2014 - Aug 2014

Two-months Volunteer

- I worked on small farms and an ecological hotel
- The sizes of the teams varied from one to 10 volunteers
- The performed work included gardening, fruit picking, care of children, care of animals, cooking and washing up, etc.

De Aimicitia (NGO)

Altea, Spain

TWO-WEEKS VOLUNTEER

Aug 2012

- Our team consisted of approximately 12 volunteers
- We collaborated with the Red Cross
- Our main objective was the cleaning of a local river and some minor municipal tasks

#### Honors & Awards \_\_\_\_\_

2011	eFellows.net Scholarship holder, High School Award	Munich, Germany
2011	Admission to the German Society of Mathematicians, High School Award	Berlin, Germany
2011	Admission to the German Society of Physicians, High School Award	Bonn, Germany

#### **Skills and Interests**

Languages

German (native), English (Level C1/2), Spanish (fluent in written and spoken language), French and Catalan (basic

knowledge)

**Programming** Python, Java, Matlab, R, Web Development (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JS, Ruby, React, Angular), Latex, Vim

**Version Control** GitHub, Mercurial

**Operating Systems** Linux / Unix, Microsoft Windows

**Software** Microsoft Office Suite, Inkscape, Gimp, Adobe Photoshop

**Other Interests** Travelling, Reading, Healthy Nutrition, Running, Strength Training, Fitness, Meditation